#### RESUME

#### Abraham Sánchez Ross

Av. Misión de San Diego #3169 Fracc. Misión del Valle, Mexicali B.C, México.

Personal, Cell (686) 216-0089 Personal (686) 565-3509

E-mail <u>abrahamsanchezr@itelcel.com</u>

#### **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

Public Accountant focused in Financials, Accounting, Cost and tax activities in corporate companies and maquiladoras with 17 years of work experience working as a business partner seeking to achieve corporate goals along with the organization. Self oriented and highly focused in results as well as good teamwork player and a quality committed partner with an excellent ability to convert new ideas into great performances for the organization in Lean accounting, six sigma philosophy and Sarbanes Oxley guidelines and Big 4 companies experience.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Fruvemex Mexicali SA de CV (1830 employees-Frozen food IMMEX industry)

2012 up to date

## Accounting Manager (Contador General)

- Responsible for develop and maintain the company accounting set of books for statutory purposes
- Supervise the General ledger group, accounts payable, cost, payroll and taxes
- Analysis of main business indicators such sales, cost and expenses
- Preparation and submit all tax and government reports such monthly income tax, VAT return, IETU, DIOT and the annual taxes with all the support documentation
- Fixed asset and depreciation calculation and control.
- Preparation and submit Monthly INEGI information (IMMEX)
- Support and provide accounting and tax information to the external auditors
- Prepare and submit payroll state tax
- Prepare special journal entries for month end close
  Up to now I have achieved the following goals:
- Cost center chart of accounts enhancement to reach quality information to the direction
- Lead Credit lines negotiations to obtain transportation units in loan agreement (best market rates and prices)

## PACCAR Inc. (Kenworth Mexicana SA de CV)

2010 - 2012.

PACCAR Financial Mexico-Direct and finance loan division.

#### Accounting Manager.

- Preparation of financial information for the financial companies of PACCAR Mexico, such as PACCAR Capital and PACCAR Financial.
- Analysis of main business indicators such as portfolio spreads and some others.
- Month end reports of the companies from the financial group, such as balance sheet, P&L, statements of cash flow, and some other comparisons and explanations in variances to forecast, prior year, prior month. Annual budgeting for PACCAR Financial activities.
- Daily, Month and year end accounting close activities.
- Supervise the General ledger and Portfolio group activities
- Financials and portfolio reports for E&Y, CNBV (National Banking Commission) and NAFIN.
- Infinium accounting system and Global treasury system success implementation as a leader.
- Cartesis corporate consolidation system implementation as a coordinator.
- Cost-Benefit Analysis for Six Sigma projects and other process enhancements.

#### 2007-2009

PACCAR Capital Mexico. Direct and Finance Loan Company.

#### Accounting supervisor.

- Preparation of financial information for the financial companies of PACCAR Mexico.
- Monthly and year end close activities
- Supervise the General Ledger group, including General ledger activities, taxes and Accounts payable.
- Gray Book preparation activities and support
- Financial statements for B10, FASB 52 and audit purposes
- Financial for NAFIN purposes.

#### 2004-2006

Paclease Mexicana. Operating Lease Division.

### General accounting supervisor.

- Preparation of financial information for the financial companies of PACCAR Mexico.
- Monthly and year end close activities
- Fixed asset controls
- Supervise the General Ledger group, including General ledger activities, taxes and Accounts payable.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2003-2004

## Daewoo Orion Mexicana SA de CV (1,500 employees maquiladora) Cost and Accounting Analyst.

- Preparation of financial information for the Direction and Corporate
- Monthly and year end close activities
- Fixed asset controls and physical inventory coordinator and leader
- General Ledger activities
- Inventory, raw materials, sub material and inventory on transit activities for accounting and analysis purposes.

#### 2000-2003

# Seagate Technology Reynosa S de RL de CV (4,500 employees maquiladora) FP&A Senior Financial Analyst.

- MRP Oracle system success implementation as a finance leader.
- Preparation of monthly corporate packages
- Responsible for develop, maintain and provide financial and Cost information
- Budget and Forecast Preparation information
- Develop of projects to enhancement processes
- Prepare special reports for corporate and Direction
- Material usage reports and analysis
- Product costing, hours per unit and inventory reports preparation and analysis
- Explanations and enhancement of variances
- Selling, General and administration expenses variances analysis
- Prepare special journal entries for month end close.

#### 1997-1999

## **Accounting Supervisor.**

- Preparation of Financials for the Corporate and Auditing purposes
- Supervise the General ledger group, taxes and Accounts payable
- Preparation and submit all tax and government reports such Tax return, VAT, annual tax return and Transfer price reports
- Selling and General expenses variances analysis
- Fixed asset inventories support

#### **OTHER EXPERIENCE:**

1997.

#### Constructora Cadena SA de CV.

General accounting, accounts reconciliations and taxes

## Agrovizión Integradora del Noroeste SA de CV

Inventory and accounts receivable accounting, Sales, Purchase, invoice accountant and physical inventory.

1995

#### Fetasa Mexicali SA de CV

General accounting, accounts reconciliations, income and fixed asset controls.

#### **EDUCATION**

High School, CBTIS 21, Certificate. 1987-1989.

Professional, UABC Universidad, Public Accountant, Degree. 1989-1994.

Tax specialty, UABC Universidad, Degree. 1996-1997

Master in Business and Administration, CETYS Universidad. In course

#### **SKILLS**

English fluent 90%. Strong excel and power point skills, excellent ability to work with groups and human relations. Lean accounting and six sigma, Command of Oracle MRP system implementation leader and super user experience (Mexicali and Reynosa sites), Hyperion Finance user, Cartesis (Corporate consolidation system) and its implementation in Mexicali, Infinium (accounting system), GTS (Global Treasury System), Contpaq and adminpaq.

## **OTHER TRAINING/COURSES**

Taxes new regulations, up to date courses

Lease and Loans accounting and legal regulations, Camara de Arrendadoras Financieras, 2010 Annual Tax Reports and Payments of Estimated Tax, Mexico Fiscal. 2010.

IFRS, Deloitte. 2010.

Mexican NIF, ANGOK, 2007

Commercial and Civil contracts, CETYS, 2006.

Derivatives accounting, PWH. 2005.

Green belt training, SEAGATE Reynosa, 2001.

Costing, Budger and Forecast Diploma, ICSE Reynosa, 2001

Custom Taxes Diploma, Grupo Logistic, 1999

#### IN HOUSE TRAINING

Effective Communication. Kenworth Mexicana, 2010

NIF vs IFRS. Deloitte, 2010.

Situational Leadership, Kenworth Mexicana, 2009.

Paccar Manager expectation, Kenworth Mexicana, 2009

Project Management, Kenworth Mexicana, 2008.

Lean Manufacturing Accounting, ITESM. 2007

#### **REFERENCES**

Martin Aguilera Calderón General Manager MHSC (Temcomex)

044(686)5805660

Rodolfo Carrillo López Latinoamerican Regional Controller, CIT Financial

044(686)2784125 Operating Lease Division Controller, Paclease Mexicana 044(686)9468591

Luis Alfonso Soto S. Leticia Alvarado

General Accountant, JCO Fertilizer

044(686)2485249